
Q: Targeted Audience?
A: This app targets the users:
1. who hate waiting in queues to get train tickets.
2. Who want to see the exact seats they will be traveling on through some seat map.



Q: What problem is solved?
A: Usually when you book the seats you don't know exactly where your seat will be so this app gives user functionality to select the seat according to user's choice with the help of seat map.



Q: App compares to other possible solutions:
A: Other available solutions are either manual or don't provide user friendly UI. This app focuses on providing best experience possible.



Q: How the app is used?
A: Open the app and you will see two options 1. Book Now and 2. Travel History
1. If you want to book the seat then you can follow the following steps:
	- Provide required details like source, destination, date and time.
	- Click on Book Now button
	- Select the train you will be traveling on
	- Select your preferred seat using seat map
	- Confirm your booking by going through payment.
2. If you have traveled before then you can see your history using the second option. This also gives you the functionality to delete the previous booking



Q: Framework/services used while making app?
A: Tool: Xcode, Language: Swift, Framework: MVC



Q: Greatest difficulty you encountered and how you solved it?
A: Making seat to look like cabin and the showing available, reserved and currently selected seat was difficult. We solved it by putting reserved seat numbers in the object train and for the next time we are checking if there is any reserved seat added in train and showing it as reserved.



Q: How you achieve minimum viable product?
A: By providing actual app which could book the seat and show user its history with user-friendly user interface. This application can be considered as MVP.



Q: Data modelling: Do the data structures reflect the problem domain?
A: Yes. We have used models for Trains and History which models the data required by them.


Q: Immutable data and idempotent methods: Is the type system used to prevent incorrect code from being written?
A: Yes, writing improper code or calling functions with incorrect data will be prevented by the system.



Q: Functional separation: Is the problem broken down into meaningful parts?
A: Yes, We first analysed the problem and broke it down to further parts like:
	- How train searching will take place?
	- How booking should be done and how its seat selection mechanism would work
	- How we can maintain travel history


Q: Loose coupling: Can parts be changed in isolation of each other?
A: Yes, We have tried to loosely couple the code. We tried to use interface rather than classes where backward communication was needed
(Example: Communication between TravelHistoryTVC.swift and TravelHistoryVC)



Q: Extensibility: How easy would it be to add, remove, or change functionality? Could a new mechanic or new content be added by changing data instead of changing code?
A: Yes, We have made models for Train and Travel History. So by providing data in these models our system will show the results accordingly. 


Q: Error handling: Are errors detected at appropriate places? Is the user prevented from entering invalid input and guided towards valid input?
A: Yes, we have restricted user to follow essential steps for example to start booking we have made it mandatory to add train details similarly to book a seat we are showing alert is user hasn't selected any seat on the seat map.

